<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CryptoLearn</title>
    <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CryptoLearn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>hello world</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/diffie_hellman/inrtoduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/diffie_hellman/inrtoduction/</guid>
      <description>The Diffie-Hellman key exchange is the method of safely developing and exchanging keys over an insecure channel. It allows two parties to establish a shared secret key over an unsecured communication channel. Unlike RSA, which is primarily used for encryption, Diffie-Hellman is focused on secure key exchange.
Working:
 Let&amp;rsquo;s say, two parties, Alice and Bob agree on two large prime numbers, p and g, and a public key exchange algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/introduction/</guid>
      <description>RSA is a widely-used public-key encryption system that is based on the mathematical properties of large prime numbers. It was one of the first practical public-key cryptosystems and is widely used for secure data transmission.
The RSA encryption process consists of two parts: key generation and encryption/decryption.
Key Generation:
 Select two large prime numbers, p and q. Compute n = p*q. n is used as the modulus for both the public and private keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Stream ciphers and block ciphers are two common types of symmetric encryption algorithms.
A stream cipher encrypts plaintext one bit or byte at a time, while a block cipher encrypts plaintext in fixed-size blocks, typically 128 or 256 bits at a time.
Stream ciphers are used in real-time applications where data is transmitted continuously, such as in wireless communications or streaming audio and video. They are efficient in terms of computation and memory usage and can encrypt data quickly and securely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift Cipher</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/shift-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/shift-cipher/</guid>
      <description>A shift cipher, also known as a Caesar cipher, is a simple encryption technique that replaces each letter of a plaintext message with a letter a fixed number of positions down the alphabet. For example, if the shift value is 3, the letter &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; would be replaced by &amp;lsquo;D&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo; would be replaced by &amp;lsquo;E&amp;rsquo;, and so on.
The shift value is also known as the key, and it determines the encryption and decryption process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affine Cipher</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/affine-ciphers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/affine-ciphers/</guid>
      <description>An Affine cipher is a type of monoalphabetic substitution cipher, in which each letter in the plaintext is mapped to a unique fixed letter in the ciphertext. This mapping is based on a mathematical function, called the Affine function, that takes two inputs: the letter of the plaintext and two encryption keys, &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;b&amp;rdquo;.
The encryption function is defined as:    C = (a*P + b) mod 26     Where:  C = the ciphertext letter (the encrypted letter) P = the plaintext letter (the original letter) a, b = the encryption keys mod 26 = the modulo operation that brings the result of the multiplication and addition within the range of 0 to 25, corresponding to the 26 letters of the alphabet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Modulus Attack</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/common-mod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/common-mod/</guid>
      <description>A common modulus attack on RSA is a type of cryptographic attack that takes advantage of the properties of RSA encryption when the same modulus is used for multiple encryptions.
In RSA, encryption is performed by raising the plaintext message to the power of the public exponent (e) and taking the remainder when divided by the modulus (n). Similarly, decryption is performed by raising the ciphertext to the power of the private exponent (d) and taking the remainder when divided by the modulus (n).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Byte XOR</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/single-byte-xor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/single-byte-xor/</guid>
      <description>Single-Byte XOR, also known as Single Character XOR, is a simple form of XOR encryption that encrypts each byte of the plaintext message using a single byte key. The encryption process is done by applying the XOR operation between the plaintext byte and the key byte.
The decryption process is the same as the encryption process, it&amp;rsquo;s just the reverse of the encryption process, the decryption key is the same key used for encryption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Subgroup Confinement Attack</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/diffie_hellman/small-subgroup-confinement-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/diffie_hellman/small-subgroup-confinement-attack/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to ghfghfcbegin</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atbash Cipher</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/atbast-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/atbast-cipher/</guid>
      <description>The Atbash Cipher is a simple form of monoalphabetic substitution cipher that uses the reverse of the alphabet as the key.
To encrypt a message, the first step is to reverse the alphabet. This can be done by writing down the alphabet, A-Z or a-z, in the usual order and then writing it down again in reverse order. Then, for each letter in the plaintext message, the corresponding letter in the reversed alphabet is used to encrypt it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world 2</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/basics/test2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repeated Key XOR</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/repeated-key-xor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/repeated-key-xor/</guid>
      <description>Repeated Key XOR is a type of encryption that uses the XOR operation to encrypt plaintext by repeatedly applying a secret key to it. In this method, the key is repeated as many times as necessary to match the length of the plaintext. The encryption process works by taking each plaintext byte and the corresponding byte of the key, and applying the XOR operation between them. The result is the ciphertext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiener Attack</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/wiener-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/wiener-attack/</guid>
      <description>The Wiener attack is a method for attacking RSA encryption when the private exponent (d) is small relative to the modulus (n). This method is named after mathematician David Wiener, who first described it in a 1990 paper.
The Wiener attack takes advantage of the fact that the private exponent (d) is typically much smaller than the modulus (n) in RSA encryption. If the private exponent (d) is small enough, it is possible to calculate the private key using the relationship between the private exponent (d) and the public exponent (e) in RSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factorisation</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/factorisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/factorisation/</guid>
      <description>Fermat&amp;rsquo;s Factorisation Method Fermat&amp;rsquo;s factorization is an algorithm for factoring integers that is based on Fermat&amp;rsquo;s Little Theorem. The theorem states that if p is a prime number, then for any integer a, the number a^p - a is an integer multiple of p. The algorithm for factoring an integer N is to find two integers a and b such that a^2 - Nb^2 = 1. If such integers are found, then N is the product of the two factors a+b and a-b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playfair Cipher</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/playfair-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/classic_cryptography/playfair-cipher/</guid>
      <description>The Playfair Cipher is a polygraphic substitution cipher that encrypts pairs of letters instead of single letters. It uses a 5x5 grid of letters (called the key square or tableau) to encrypt pairs of letters.
To encrypt a message, the first step is to create the key square. This is done by choosing a keyword and writing it in a 5x5 grid, filling the remaining spaces with the remaining letters of the alphabet in alphabetical order, omitting the letter &amp;lsquo;J&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transposition ciphers</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/transposition-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/transposition-cipher/</guid>
      <description>Transposition ciphers are a type of encryption technique that rearrange the positions of the letters in the plaintext to produce the ciphertext. The plaintext is rearranged according to a specific rule or method, such as a regular pattern or a secret key. The process of encryption is reversible, meaning that the original plaintext can be obtained by rearranging the ciphertext using the same rule or method.
There are several types of transposition ciphers, such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coppersmith&#39;s Method</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/coppersmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/rsa/coppersmith/</guid>
      <description>Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack is a technique used in cryptography to factorize the private key of a public key encryption system. It is applied specifically to RSA encryption, which is one of the most widely used public key encryption systems.
In RSA encryption, the private key is generated by multiplying two prime numbers. Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack exploits the low-order bits of the private key to find the prime factors. The technique is based on the observation that the modular reduction operation used in RSA encryption does not affect the lower order bits of the private key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modes of block cipher</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/modes-of-block-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/steam_block_ciphers/modes-of-block-cipher/</guid>
      <description>A block cipher is a type of symmetric key encryption that encrypts data in fixed-size blocks (typically 64 or 128 bits). There are several different modes of encryption that can be used with a block cipher to encrypt data of any size:
Electronic Code Book (ECB) mode: This is the simplest and most basic mode of encryption. Each block of plaintext is independently encrypted with the same key, resulting in a block of ciphertext of the same size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Where to begin</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/where_to_begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/patterns/where_to_begin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cupper</title>
      <link>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/print-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victim1307.github.io/cryptolearn/print-version/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t want to edit this file :-)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
